<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
    <spell>
      <name>Absolute Command</name>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <level>4</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <ritual>NO</ritual>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a pair of small gloves fitted with a conduit and worth 100 g)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <text>You can control a construct you have built with a challenge rating of 6 or less. You can manipulate objects with your construct as precisely as its construction allows, and you perceive its surroundings through its sensory inputs as if you inhabited its body. The construct uses the caster's Proficiency bonus (modified by the construct's Strength and Dexterity scores). You can use the manipulators of the construct to perform any number of skill-based tasks, using the construct's Strength and Dexterity modifiers when using skills based on those particular abilities.\nYour body remains immobile, as if paralyzed, for the duration of the spell. The construct must remain within 100 feet of you. If it moves beyond this distance, the spell immediately ends and the caster's mind returns to his body.
        At higher levels. When you cast this spell using higher-level spell slots, you may control a construct with a challenge rating 2 higher for each slot level you use above 4th. The construct’s range also increases by 10 feet for each slot level.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Acid Rain</name>
        <classes>Sorcerer, Wizard, Warlock</classes>
        <level>5</level>
        <school>C</school>
        <ritual>NO</ritual>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <components>V, S, M (a drop of acid)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <text>You unleash a storm of swirling acid in a cylinder 20 feet wide and 30 feet high centered on a point you can see. The area is heavily obscured by the driving acidfall. A creature that starts its turn in the area or that enters the area for the first time on its turn takes 6d6 acid damage, or half damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes half damage from the acid (as if it had made a successful saving throw) automatically at the start of its first turn after leaving the affected area.
        At higher levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target an additional willing creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
        <roll>6d6</roll>
        <roll>7d6</roll>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <roll>9d6</roll>
        <roll>10d6</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
    <name>Adjust Positioning</name>
    <classes>Bard, Cleric, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <level>1</level>
    <school>T</school>
    <ritual>NO</ritual>
    <time>1 bonus action</time>
    <range>30 ft</range>
    <components>V</components>
    <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
    <text>You adjust the location of an ally to a better tactical
position. You move one willing creature 5 feet. This
movement does not provoke opportunity attacks. The
creature moves bodily through the intervening space
(as opposed to teleporting or gating), so there can be no
physical blockage (wall, door) between them.
At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using
a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target an
additional willing creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
    <roll></roll>
</spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Afflict Line</name>
        <classes>Cleric, Warlock</classes>
        <level>9</level>
        <school>N</school>
        <ritual>YES</ritual>
        <time>1 hour</time>
        <range>1 mile</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a statuette carved in the likeness of the victim worth 1%2C250 gp)</components>
        <duration>Permanent; one generation</duration>
        <text>You invoke the darkest curses upon your victim and his or her descendants. This spell does not require that you have a clear path to your target, only that your target is within range. Your target must make a successful Wisdom saving throw or be cursed until the magic is dispelled. The victim has disadvantage on ability checks and saving throws made with the ability score that you choose when you cast the spell. In addition, the target's firstborn offspring is also targeted by the curse. The firstborn is allowed a saving throw of their own if they currently live, or they make one upon their birth if they're not yet born when the spell is cast. If the target's firstborn has already died, the curse passes to their next oldest offspring. 
      Ritual Focus. If you expend your ritual focus, the curse becomes hereditary, passing from firstborn to firstborn for the entire length of the family's lineage until one of them successfully saves against the curse and throws off your dark magic.</text>
        <roll></roll>
    </spell>

    <spell>
	<name>Amplify Ley Field</name>
	<classes>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock</classes>
	<level>5</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 action</time>
	<range>Self (10 ft radius sphere)</range>
	<components>V, S</components>
	<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
	<text>You create a faintly shimmering field of charged energy
around yourself. Within that area, the intensity of ley lines
you're able to draw on increases from weak to strong, or
from strong to titanic.
If no ley lines are near enough for you to draw on, you
can treat the area of the spell itself as an unlocked, weak
ley line.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>    

<spell>
	<name>Analyze Device</name>
	<classes>Bard</classes>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>D</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 hour</time>
	<range>Touch</range>
	<components>V, S, M (a complete set of clockworker's tools)</components>
	<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
	<text>You discover all mechanical properties, mechanisms,
and functions of a single construct or clockwork device,
including how to activate or deactivate those functions, if
appropriate.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>

<spell>
	<name>Angelic Guardian</name>
	<classes>Cleric, Paladin, Warlock</classes>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>C</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 action</time>
	<range>30 feet</range>
	<components>V, S</components>
	<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
	<text>You conjure a minor celestial manifestation to protect a
creature you can see within range. A faintly glowing figure
resembling a human head and shoulders hovers within
5 feet of the target for the duration. The figure moves
to interpose itself between the target and any incoming
attacks, granting the target +2 to AC.
If the target fails a Dexterity saving throw while the spell
is active, it can use its reaction to roll a new save. The spell
then ends.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>

<spell>
	<name>Animate Construst</name>
	<classes></classes>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>T</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 action</time>
	<range>30 feet</range>
	<components>V, S, M (a construct body of appropriate size)</components>
	<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes (see below)</duration>
	<text>This spell animates a carefully prepared construct of Tiny
size. The object acts immediately, on your turn, and can
attack your opponents to the best of its ability. You can
direct it not to attack, to attack particular enemies, or to
perform other actions. You choose the object to animate,
and you can change that choice each time you cast the
spell. The cost of the body to be animated is 10 gp x its
hit points. The body can be reused any number of times,
provided it isn't severely damaged or destroyed.
If no prepared construct body is available, you can
animate a mass of loose metal or stone instead. Before
casting, the loose objects must be arranged in a suitable
shape (taking up to a minute), and the construct's hit
points are halved.
An animated construct has a Constitution of 10,
Intelligence and Wisdom 3, and Charisma 1. Other
characteristics are determined by the construct’s size as
follows.
At Higher Levels. Casting this spell using higher level
spell slots allows you to increase the size of the construct
animated, as shown on the table.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>

<spell>
	<name>Arcane Sight</name>
	<classes>Sorcerer, Warlock</classes>
	<level>8</level>
	<school>D</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 round</time>
	<range>Touch</range>
	<components>V, S, M (a piece of clear quartz)</components>
	<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
	<text>The recipient of this spell gains the benefits of both true
seeing and detect magic for 1 hour, and also knows the name
and effect of every spell he or she witnesses during arcane
sight's duration.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>

<spell>
	<name>Armored Heart</name>
	<classes>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock</classes>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>C</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 bonus action</time>
	<range>Touch</range>
	<components>V,S,M (5 gp worth of mithral dust sprinkled on the target’s skin)</components>
	<duration>1 round</duration>
	<text>The targeted creature gains resistance to bludgeoning,
slashing, and piercing damage. This resistance can be
overcome with adamantine or magical weapons.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>

<spell>
	<name>Armored Shell</name>
	<classes>Sorcerer, Warlock</classes>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>C</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 bonus action</time>
	<range>Self</range>
	<components>V, S, M (a rivet)</components>
	<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
	<text>This spell creates a suit of magical studded leather armor
(AC 12). It does not grant you proficiency in its use.
Casters without the appropriate armor proficiency suffer
disadvantage on any ability check, saving throw, or attack
roll that involves Strength or Dexterity and cannot cast
spells.
At Higher Levels. Casting armored shell using a
higher‑level spell slot creates stronger armor%3A a chain shirt
(AC 13) at level 2, scale mail (AC 14) at level 3, chain mail
(AC 16) at level 4, and plate armor (AC 18) at level 5.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>

<spell>
	<name>Aspect of the Dragon</name>
	<classes>Sorcerer</classes>
	<level>7</level>
	<school>T</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 action</time>
	<range>Self</range>
	<components>V, S, M (a dragon scale)</components>
	<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
	<text>By tapping into your very blood, this spell draws out the
ancient nature inside, demonstrating to the world you are
not like the rest; you are descended from dragons. This
spell allows you to assume the form of any dragon-type
creature of challenge 10 or less.
You assume the hit points and Hit Dice of the new form.
When you revert to your normal form, you return to the
number of hit points you had before you transformed.
If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any
excess damage carries over to your normal form. As long
as the excess damage doesn’t reduce your normal form to
0 hit points, you aren’t knocked unconscious.
You retain the benefit of any features from your class,
race, or other source and can use them, provided that your
new form is physically capable of doing so. You can speak
only if the dragon can normally speak.
When you transform, you choose whether your
equipment falls to the ground, merges into the new form,
or is worn by it. Worn equipment functions normally, but
equipment doesn’t change shape or size to match the new
form. Any equipment that the new form can’t wear must
either fall to the ground or merge into the new form. The
GM has final say on whether the new form can wear or use
a particular piece of equipment. Equipment that merges
has no effect in that state.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>

<spell>
	<name>Auspicious Warning</name>
	<classes>Bard, Sorcerer</classes>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>D</school>
	<ritual>NO</ritual>
	<time>1 reaction, which you take when an ally rolls an attack, ability check, or saving throw</time>
	<range>30 feet</range>
	<components>V</components>
	<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
	<text>Just in time, you call out a fortunate warning to a creature.
The target rolls a d4 and adds the number rolled to one
attack roll, ability check, or saving throw that they have
just made and uses the new result for determining success
or failure.</text>
	<roll></roll>
</spell>
</compendium>